## OPERATIONS MANAGER

Professional Summary

Operations Manager with 20+ years of experience in a healthcare setting. Effective leadership skills include planning, organizing, and executing operations in order to provide for quality customer service and high customer satisfaction, financial profitability, and a trained and satisfied workforce.

**Education and Training** 

Bachelor of Science , Management 2007 Kaplan University i1/4 City , State , US Bachelor of Science: Management, 2007 Kaplan University - Davenport, IA

Associate of Applied Science , Management 2005 Kaplan University i1/4 City , State , US Associate of Applied Science: Management, 2005 Kaplan University - Davenport, IA

Skill Highlights

3.5 million dollar P & L management Consistently meet goals Multi-site operations management Efficient multi-tasker Critical thinking Conflict resolution Customer service-oriented? Deadline-oriented Quality assurance and control Consistently meet goals Process improvement Extensive HIPAA training and knowledge Detail-oriented Knowledge of meaningful use metrics Experience with multiple electronic medical records Knowledge of Hedis measures systems Risk management

Professional Experience

Operations Manager May 2008 to Apr 2015

Fidelity National Information Services it/4 King Of Prussia, PA Directly supervised 34 field associates an area manager and two site coordinators Responsible for recruiting and hiring competent, qualified staff Ensured that field staff was oriented, trained and their competence assessed (including but not limited to ROI & HIPAA), maintained, demonstrated and improved continually Prepared bi-weekly payroll reports, monthly and weekly turnaround time and pending reports, and yearly associate evaluations Set up and managed multiple full-service and clinic route accounts within the district Routinely met with HIM directors and managers and reviewed account and employee performance Prepared monthly KPI reports, utilizing Cognos, to monitor the financial metrics of my district including revenue mix, revenue per business day, labor per payroll day, and labor productivity standards Developed new business opportunities with new and existing customers and worked closely with sales directors to pursue and close these opportunities Introduced and marketed new products and services offered by the company Assisted with contract renegotiations

District Manager Jul 2002 to Apr 2008

Planet Fitness Inc. i1/4 Greenville, TX Originally hired as a floating manager responsible for starting up new accounts in Chicago, Arizona, New York, and Wisconsin Directly supervised two team leaders and ten field associates Evaluated sites with backlogs, including retraining of staff and assisting with site cleanup Responsible for recruiting and hiring competent, qualified staff Ensured that field staff was oriented, trained and their competence assessed (including but not limited to ROI & HIPAA), maintained, demonstrated and improved continually Prepared bi-weekly payroll reports, monthly and weekly turnaround time and pending reports, and yearly associate evaluations Monitored associate productivity Set up and managed multiple full-service accounts within the district Routinely met with HIM directors and managers and reviewed account and employee performance Developed new business opportunities with new and existing customers Introduced and marketed new products and services offered by the company

Administrator Oct 1996 to Jun 2002

The University Of Kansas Hospital it/4 Hays, KS Returned on a part-time basis until 1998 when a full-time management position was offered Promoted to District Manager in December 1999, then promoted to Regional Manager in December 2000 Directly supervised 24 field associates and two team leaders Responsible for recruiting and hiring competent, qualified staff Ensured that field staff was oriented, trained and their competence assessed continually Prepared bi-weekly payroll reports, monthly and weekly turnaround time and pending reports, and yearly associate evaluations Set up and managed multiple full-service accounts within the district Routinely met with HIM directors and managers and reviewed account and employee performance Developed new business opportunities with new and existing customers Introduced and marketed new products and services offered by the company Installed and demonstrated company software In addition to managing Ohio territory, also assumed the position of interim site manager in Nashville, Tennessee. Traveled each week for five days from August 2001 until March 2002 to manage the daily operations, including supervising eight employees, at a large hospital Managed office for eight physicians' medical specialty societies and served as executive director on each society's executive committee Completed bookkeeping tasks including preparation of financial statements, payables, and receivables as well as financial reports Coordinated special events and dinners including preparation of fliers and booklets for each individual society Prepared paperwork and solicited funds from pharmaceutical companies for the continuing education of doctors Published monthly newsletters Made collection calls to society members delinquent with yearly dues Supervised one office assistant. Certifications

HIPAA

Professional Affiliations

Midwest Medical Records Association, Inc. - Schaumburg, IL

Skills

Associate, Bi, Business Intelligence, Employee Performance, New Products, Payroll, Recruiting, Hipaa, Roi, Operations, Coda, Cognos, Ibm Cognos, Metrics, Operations Manager, Sales, With Sales, Accounts In, New Accounts, Basis, Territory, Time Management, Bookkeeping, Collection, Financial Reports, Financial Statements, Office Assistant, Payables, Receivables, Customer Service, Detail-oriented, Healthcare, Hedis, Leadership Skills, Medical Records, Million, Multi-tasker, Operations Management, Process Improvement, Quality Assurance, Receptionist, Retail Sales, Risk Management, Satisfaction, Trading, Training